我要蔬菜杂烩配白米饭
Uh, yeah... can I get the mixed vegetables and white rice?
- 好嘞 蔬菜杂烩加白米饭 - 哇靠
- Okay, mixed vegetables,white rice. - Damn, Du'.
你把这当高级餐厅啊
You actin' like this some fancy-ass spot.
不就一破中餐店儿么
It ain't nothing but a Chink joint.
- 我要点了 - 那就点呗 说了我请了
- I'm-a order. - Then do it.I said I got it.
瞧这黑鬼 钱甩得哗哗响
Look at this nigger flashin' his shit
跟黑道大哥似的
Iike some big-time gangster.
哪里 一代少侠嘛
Yeah, Na' a righteous hustler.
我就想请请你们大家
Man, I'm just treating y'all, that's all.
哥对手下小弟向来大方
You know I like to keep it real with the little people.
你再说遍
Man, fuck you, man.
我说你呢 说你呢
- I was talking about you. - I was talking about you.
要吃点啥?
May I help you?
来个牛肉拉面浇火鸡油吧
Can I order the yakame with turkey grease?
牛肉拉面喂
Yakame, noodles-
- 这家伙居然点火鸡油 - 怎么啦?
- This nigger ordered turkey grease. - What's wrong, yo?
我妈她就一直这么点的
I mean, my mom, she get it all the time.
你还真他妈是问题少年啊
Yo, you is really one of them at-risk children,
- 我说 Dukie - 喂 让他去嘛
- you know that, Dukie? - Yo, man, leave him alone, son.
行了 我付账 多少钱?
Yeah, I got it. How much?
- 四块 - 有什么好笑的
- $4.00. - Why is it so funny?
他们逗你玩呢
They just goofin' on you.
我点牛肉面怎么了?
What's wrong with me ordering yakame?
牛肉面没啥
Nothing wrong with you ordering yakame.
加火鸡油是那些醉鬼为了
It's just the turkey grease that makes the drunks,
快点把喝下去的酒给吐出来
you know, throw up all that liquor they was drinking,
好继续接着灌
go back to swilling that shit.
- 这玩意太他妈好吃了 - 要吃自己买去
- Man, this shit is good. - Why don't you buy your own food?
就给你这点儿
This is all you getting.
吃完别问我要了
Don't ask for no more of that.
简直好吃到爆啊
That shit tastes good as hell.
你们听说小Kevin的事儿了么
Yo, y'all heard about what happened to Little Kevin?
咋了
What?
死啦
He be dead.
- 在某个空屋躺着呢 - 为啥?
- He up in them vacants. - Why?
惹了不该惹的吧
Fucked up somewhere, I suppose.
哇靠
Uh-oh.
小兔崽子在我的地盘儿上干啥呢
What the fuck you little hoppers doing on my avenue?
- 吃饭 - 吃屎吧
- Eating. - Shit you are.
我看你们是蹲点想抢钱包吧
You're probably setting up to snatch a purse.
回你们黑鬼自己的地儿呆着去
Get the fuck back on the reservation  where your black asses belong.
你想怎么滴啊 小子?
How you feeling, little man?
要我把饭扣你头上哇
Need a hand with that food:
我说了快滚
I said get.
你们听到么 "我的地盘"
Yo, y'all hear that shit? "My avenue."
明明是你是我是大家的
It's just as much ours as it is his.
Walker就他妈一垃圾
Walker be evil, yo.
除了偷东西就是打人
He be thieving and smackin' folk down.
得让他知道 出来混迟早是要还的
Yo, we should get him back on the  payback tip for all the dirt he do.
你想跟条子单挑?
You want to throw down with police?
没说正面单挑嘛 就弄下他
I don't mean go at him direct, but, you know, hurt him.
划个车胎啊什么的
Like, slash his tires or some shit.
不如往车上粘避孕套吧
We could stick condoms on his car.
给他点颜色瞧瞧
That'd send a message.
可粘哪种呢?
Yeah, but what kind?
或者往挡风玻璃上贴粘纸
We should slap bumper stickers on his windshield.
这东西不好弄掉啊
I mean, they is hard to get off.
等等
Hold on, wait wait wait.
Walker警官是不是常去Stockton那家俱乐部
Do Officer Walker go to that club on Stockton,
西区警察开派对那家?
the one where the Western police party?
我在那儿见过他的车
I seen his car there.
看我的吧
I got this one.
火线重案组 第四季 第11集
the.wire.s04e11
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
"常在河边走 哪能不湿鞋" -McNulty
我个人虽深表同情
And as much as I empathize,
但我只能说申诉这个问题
I can only tell you that there is a process
它总要有个流程的
for complaints like this one.
别用流程糊弄我们 市长先生
Don't sell us on process, Mr. Mayor.
市警局这样对咱也不是一年两年的事儿了
We've had years of this kind of treatment from city police.
请您务必理解
You need to understand
这对我们来说是当务之急
we view this as an affront to the cloth.
我们申请平民协查组
We've asked for a civilian review board
已经十几年了 没有它我们怎么信任
for decades now. Absent that, how can we trust
任何针对申诉的调查呢?
any investigation of any complaint?
抱歉先生们 据我所知
Forgive me, gentlemen, but last I checked,
局里不仅有一名黑人局长 还有一位黑人内务部主管
the department had a black commissioner and a black l.I.D. director.
问题在于整个系统
The problem is systemic.
至于Burrell局长
And as to Commissioner Burrell-
据我们所知他的权力范围有限
we understand that his authority is now limited.
市长先生 在这种情况下
Mr. Mayor, when it comes to matters like this one,
您还指望我们怎么信任Rawls副官?
do you expect us to have faith in Deputy Rawls?
我希望你们不要对局里的回应抱有偏见
I expect you'll be good enough not to  prejudge the department's response
调查毕竟还没开始嘛
before the investigation even begins,
我也没有偏见嘛
as I won't prejudge it.
请你们相信我对此次事件的调查非常重视
I can only tell you that l take this incident very seriously,
务必还事实一个真相
and that I will pursue all of the facts.
好吧 市长先生
Well, Mr. Mayor,
您说过大门随时敞开
you said you would have an open door,
目前还算是说到做到了
and so far I credit you for keeping that promise.
为你们 我的大门永远敞开
And my door will always be open to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们在Royce任期内都没能申请到平民协查组
If they couldn't get civilian review out of a Royce administration,
凭什么指望我能给他们
how can they think they're gonna get it from me?
他们这是试探你呢
They're just testing you here,
看你在种族问题上有多软弱
trying to see how vulnerable you feel on the racial stuff.
还有Burrell的事儿 也不放过
On Burrell, too, for what it's worth.
平民协查组这事儿不能碰
Well, civilian review is a nonstarter.
你现在答应了他们
You go now there now,
接下来四年都得为这些部长弯腰低头
you'll be bending over for four years for the ministers.
那怎么办? 给他们点甜头 炒掉几个白痴警察?
So what? I throw them a bone  and fire some idiot cop?
这么干 基层警察准恨我恨得要死
By pressing that, the average beat cop's
可没有自上而下的支持
gonna hate my guts, and I ain't gonna change
又什么实事都办不了
anything around without rank-and-file support.
不炒他 你可就要把
You don't fire him, you're going to piss off
绝大部分黑人政要统统给得罪喽
most of the black political infrastructure.
嗯 美味 上任第一碗屎
Mm, yummy. My first bowl of shit.
这边画圈
Circle that right there.
然后按那个键
And you press that right there.
学习时间了
It's work time.
你们没事儿干吗 数据写下来没有?
You guys got work to do? You write down that data?
- 嗯 - 好的
- Yeah. - All right.
Charlene 你哪部分不懂?
Charlene, what don' you understand?
全都不懂
None of it.
好吧 我们看看怎样让你搞懂
Okay, let's see if we can find a way you can get it, okay?
直径是多少?
What's the diameter?
- 啥? - 是7
- ?? - It's seven.
很好 那么它的一半是什么呢?
Good. Okay, what's half of that?
这怎么能分一半呢
You can't take half of it.
好吧 就比方说你有10美元
Okay, let's say you have $10
你分一半给Jasmine
and you gave half of it to Jasmine.
干嘛要分给她
Why I do that?
打比方嘛
Well, just pretend, okay?
你给她一半 她有多少啊?
You give her half, how much does she have?
- 切 5块呗 - 很好
- Duh, $5. - Good.
那么我们再比方你有7美元
Now let's say this time you have $7
给了她一半 那她有多少?
and you give her half, how much does she have?
3块5毛
$3.50.
好 那么...
Good, so...
Prez老师 快看
Yo, Mr. Prez, check this out.
哦
Oh!
我们干嘛不去他家踩点 再一路跟过来?
Why we no pick him up at his casa, follow him from there?
干嘛 好再跟丢一次啊?
Why, so we can lose him here again?
亲爱的 谁晓得他一定会走这条路?
Papa, nothin' say he got to come back through this way, you know?
万一他换条路走呢?
What if he take another road...?
好吧 我们明天去他家等他
All right.We pick him up from his casa tomorrow.
- 嘀咕啥呢 别嘀咕 - 没嘀咕 咱死守还不行么
Poutin'. Don't pout.
对不住了 兄弟 对不住
Lo siento, baby. Lo siento.
你看...
Hey, now...
这不出现了么
there she blow.
好
All right, then.
大家都知道 在街上盯着望风的看需要胆量
So we agree staring down a stick-up boy  on a corner takes courage,
也知道 去Cheltenham或Hickeyand过夜
and we agree it takes courage to go overnight
也需要胆量
to Cheltenham or Hickey.
需要胆量的事儿多了
This is a good list,
但除了在街上 还能想到别的例子么
but are there any examples we can make outside of being on a corner?
我需要一名志愿者
I need a volunteer.
别找我
Not me.
- 你呢 Albert? - 不干
- What about you, Albert? - No.
还当志愿者呢 连干嘛都不知道
You volunteer and you don't know what for,
当我傻的啊
you ain't got brains.
好吧 我需要一名志愿者站在这个箱子上
All right, then, I need a volunteer to stand on this box
蒙上眼睛 往后倒
blindfolded, fall off
在落地之前由我们接住他
and let us catch him before he hits the ground.
- Albert? - 太他妈傻逼了
- Albert? - That's fucking stupid.
你呢 Namond?
What about you, Namond?
等等 让我搞搞清楚
Wait wait wait, let me get this right.
你让我站在那个箱子上
So you want me to stand up on that box,
蒙上眼 往下倒
put a blindfold on, fall,
指望着这帮怂逼能接住我?
and expect these weak-ass clowns to catch me?
才不呢
Hell, no.
好吧 你们敢让我摔倒 有你们好看的
Hey, yo, y'all drop me, and we gonna have more than words.
好吧
A'ight.
好了 大家围拢过来
All right, everybody gather around.
妈的
Oh, shit.
准备好了 数到三
You ready? On three.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
让他摔
Let him drop.
哇 这玩意儿爽啊
Whoa! Shit! Oh, that shit was right.
好了 下一个谁想来?
All right, who wants to go next?
- Albert? - 我才不要玩这种傻逼游戏呢
- Albert? - I ain't doing no stupid shit like that!
你去死 你们这帮傻逼统统去死
Fuck you, and fuck all y'all bitches.
反正我们也不待见你
We don't like your ass anyway.
够了 够了
Settle down, settle down.
今日特别推荐 迷你好时巧克力
Yo, today's specials are those little Hershey bars,
2毛5分三个
three for a dime.
还有各种各样好东西
And I got all your other favorites, too.
Deante 给你带了甘草糖
Yo, Deante, I got your licorice-
红的黑的都有
red and black both.
告密的Randy
Snitchin' Randy.
老子撞大运了嘿 快看
Well, I'll be blessed, yo. Lookit.
行了吧 追到这儿够了吧
This is good? We put him here?
跟Joe老大一起的那个长脚
That tall man with Prop Joe:
真的 在这地界儿
Yo, for real, on this caper
真是学得越多 懂得越少啊
the more we learn, the less we know.
- 能走了? - 不 待着
- We can go? - No, we stay.
老爹 我得闪了
Papa, I need to go.
我说了待着 Renaldo 你聋了啊?
I say we stay, Renaldo. What's wrong, yo?
不不 我是说"方便"
No no, I mean "go."
憋不住啦 咱在车里坐太久啦
We been in the car too many hours.
要不上巷子里蹲着去
Whether you squat in an alley
要不给自己找一痰盂
or sittin' on a porcelain throne,
不能打草惊蛇嘛 是不?
don't really change the moment, now do it?
不开心?
Rough day?
憋在心里没啥好处啊
Doesn't help to hold it in.
你他妈知道个啥?
What the fuck you know?
说出来说不定我们能帮忙呢
If you tell me, maybe we can help.
没事儿
Ain't nothing.
好了 Albert 你在班上一直表现不错
Look, come on, Albert, you been doing real good in this class.
除了今天都很好嘛
Real good till today.
说说看吧
Just give it a try.
我昨天回家 发现我妈躺在沙发上
I went home yesterday. My mom's on the couch.
她死了
She dead.
姥姥说最好还是来上学 可...
Me-maw said best l come to school, but...
你想妈妈了吧
Yeah, you wanted to be with your mom.
能不想嘛
Of course you did.
你们有些在缉毒部门见过我
Some of you know me from narcotics work,
有些从前在西区干的时候认识我
some from earlier if you worked the Western district,
有些是今天第一次见到
and some of you I'm meeting for the first time.
但我今天唯一想说的是
But the only point l'd really like to make here today
这是一个过渡的时刻
is that this is a transitional time
不仅是我们局里 而且是整个市
for this department and for the city as a whole.
我们有了一位新市长 一位新检察官
We have a new mayor and a new state's attorney,
他们两位都急切地想做出改变
and they both feel like they have a mandate for change.
关键是以市长对待犯罪的态度
The point is that given the mayor's position on crime
和选举的结果来看 我们可以期冀真正的改变
and given the outcome of the election, we can expect certain enhancements.
真的?
Oh, really?
改变在不远的将来可望实现
Certain improvements may be forthcoming in the near future.
所以我们需要大家的反馈
So we're looking for feedback here,
哪些是大家为更好地打击犯罪
some input as to what we need
所需要或者所不要的
more of or less of to better work murders.
- 更好的证人保护计划 - 更主动的调查取证
- Better witness protection. - More proactive investigation.
涨工资
Pay raise.
耶
Yeah!
- 更好的实验设备 更多在值技术人员 - 更多加班工资
- Better lab work. More techs on duty. - More overtime.
更多威士忌!
More Scotch!
更多备案时间 真的
More time for case prep. Seriously.
更多妞 奔放的妞
More women. Loose women.
加薪 加两位数的
Pay hike, double-digits.
更多更好 更多更好 更多更好
Mo' better, mo' better, mo' better.
这些就是我们所要的
That's what we want.
听着像是要换天了吧?
Sounds like a new day, don't it?
局里总算能添置些需要的了
Department's finally gonna get what it needs.
检察官办公室也是
State's attorney's office, too.
换天
A new day.
这俩站一块倒是挺有夫妻相
They make a nice couple, anyway.
很期待与您合作 警监
Looking forward to working with you, Colonel.
这是现任市长亲笔签字的文件
That's signed by a now-inaugurated mayor
要求警局负责人避免大规模抓捕
ordering his police commanders to avoid mass arrests.
尤其强调社区民警
Community-based policing and
和高级执法人员
high-end enforcements are to be emphasized.
Burrell也收到一份了吧
I take it Burrell got a copy.
亲手给的
In person.
我不明白
I don't see it.
干嘛不炒了那狗娘养的?
Why not just fire the fucking asshole?
市长也在权衡利弊
The mayor is weighing his options.
这算什么意思?
What the fuck does that mean?
炒了Burrell 我们必将面临
To fire Burrell, we're going to need more
政治资本的短缺
political capital than we have right now.
说起这茬 还有件相关的
Speaking of which, it brings us to another
小小事务
Iittle piece of business.
- 部长们那事儿 - 这情况很微妙
- The thing with the minister. - It's a delicate situation.
部长们催着要平民观察组
The ministers are pressing for a civilian review,
员佐级别的肯定不愿意听
which I know the rank and file don't want to hear,
但这事直接关系到Burrell的处境
but it speaks directly to the situation with Burrell.
如果为了这起事件产生财政支出
If we expend capital defending this incident-
我明白了 你们想炒了那警察
I get it. You want the cop fired.
不 我们完全不是这个意思
No, we're not saying that at all.
市长并不想掺和
The mayor doesn't want to interfere with
警局的日常事务
the everyday workings of the department.
但这事得权衡轻重
But it's a balancing act.
要回应得漂亮 两边都不得罪
Our response has to be smart and evenhanded,
尤其牵涉到种族问题
in a racial sense, especially.
没理解错的话 要用巧计
If I'm hearing you, it's about perception.
正是
Exactly.
内务部倒是有位黑人指挥官 但是他欠Burrell人情
I.I.D. has a black commander, but he's beholden to Burrell.
有机会肯定会兴风作浪
He'll stir shit with this if he can.
把该名警官调往刑事罪案调查科
The sergeant in question is assigned to C.I.D.
那里新指挥官Daniels
His new commander is Daniels.
此人很能干 是黑人 政治上又中立
He's smart, he's black, and politically neutral.
- 你意下如何? - 我看行
- That work for you? - Works for us.
谁啊 我说谁啊
Who that? I said, who's that?
回家住还是就回来看看
You home or you just visiting?
回家住行么
Home if I can.
好吧 过来坐火边上吧
All right. Get by the fire if you want.
还剩几根热狗 你饿不饿?
I got a couple of dogs left. You hungry?
Jo Jo那边没戏唱
Shit weren't working out with Jo-Jo and them.
说我欠他东西 其实根本是别人干的
Said I owed him some cheddar on some shit some other boy did.
我反正不想多嘴
I don't want to make no noise on that, though.
他们就冲你来了
They pressin' you.
那啥...
You know...
还是跟我吧 咱马上能把债给还了
get with me, and we pay 'em right back, okay?
不 你说的那些话
No, all that shit you been sayin' to me
一直在我脑子里转
goin' through my head.
别去想它了 什么都别想了
Forget about that. Forget about all that.
要不是我逼你走
If I wouldn't have pushed you off,
你也不会沦落到街头
you would have never been up on that corner.
可我干什么都是个熊样
But everything I do I be fucking up.
站那儿都不像自己了
Whole time it feel like it wasn't me on that corner.
就想逃跑
I just wanted to get away.
你这不回家了嘛
Well, you're here now, ain't you? Right?
回家做自己 不挺好?
This is you, right here, right now, okay?
你那衬衫要烧出洞来啦
You're burning a hole in that shirt, man.
操你妈的
Fuck- you fucked me all up
我一看你从那门走进来  就啥都顾不得啦
when I saw you walking through the door, Sherrod.
妈的
Oh, shit.
你看咋样
What you think, huh?
我半价买来的
You know, I get half price for this.
行了 把帽子脱了吧
All right, take your hat off, man.
别把热狗给烤焦了
Don't burn them pimp steaks, huh:
这么久
Took long enough.
Dukie 你真要这么干?
Yo, Dukie, you sure about this?
不是我不挺你
I mean, I'm with y'all.
你们是我兄弟
Y'all my boys like that.
兄弟为我 我为兄弟
Y'all there for me, I'm there for y'all.
可我越想越觉得这事儿悬
I'm really starting to think this is some fucked-up shit.
Walker警官他是狗娘养的
I mean, Officer Walker's a shady motherfucker,
可丫是警察啊
but he's police.
我们就按Michael的法子 吓唬吓唬他
We do it Michael's way, we send a message.
是老子动手 又不用你们干
You ain't got to do what I got to do.
还是抽签决定吧
We drew straws, Na'.
走吧
Let's go.
全在这儿了?
This is everything?
Hauk警官的报告 部长们的
Sergeant Hauk's statement, the ministers',
其他警官的报告 都在这里了
statements of the other officers- it's all there.
没有独立目击证人
No independent witnesses, huh:
我觉得这事儿烟幕不小火势倒不大
It's a lot of smoke, but I'm not feeling much in the way of fire.
也许有严重的执法态度问题
It was a strong case for discourtesy.
但并无证据表明涉及种族宗教歧视
True, but no indication of racial or religious overtones.
暴力执法的指责更是牵强
And the brutality allegation is a stretch.
我查过G.O.C.-7法案
I've gone over G.O.C.-7.
也有意尽快了结此事
I'm up to speed with the matrix,
但处理此事经费有限
but since the buck stops with me on this one,
你说我该怎么办
walk me through my options.
轻度伤害 你可以出一份总结报告
Minor offenses, you can issue a summary judgment-
让他停薪留任一段时间
a period of extra duty without pay,
接受监督和辅导 诸如此类
guidance and counseling, the like.
如果Hauk对你的决定不满
Or if Sergeant Hauk fights your decision
或如有更实质性的起诉
or if there's a more substantive charge,
那就下拨至庭审处理
it goes downstairs to a trial board.
可能做停职处理?
And possible termination?
我问你
Let me ask you-
如果此案事关部长们
if the minister's connected,
又在众目睽睽之下
and if all eyes are on this one,
指挥官态度如何?
what does command want to see happen?
市政厅态度又如何?
What does City Hall want to see happen?
市政厅只希望有人做正确的事
City Hall just wants someone to do the right thing,
具体如何不管
whatever that is.
副局 你往这儿一坐 让我做正确的事?
You're sitting here, Deputy, telling me to just do the right thing?
这好事儿不常有 我知道
Doesn't happen often, I know.
嘿 你干嘛呢 快过来
Hey! What are you doing? Come here!
小兔崽子 看我不逮着你
You motherfucker, I'll get your little ass!
手举起来 贱人
Come on, show me hands, bitch.
去你妈的小兔崽子 老子可是警察
Back the fuck up, little hopper, I'm police.
我知道 不就是个喜欢欺压黑人的警察
Yeah, I know, you the police who like to fuck with a nigger.
转过身去
Turn around.
嘿 嘿
Hey hey, yo!
下一枪你可别想活着听到了
You ain't gonna hear the next one.
给我跪下 双腿交叉 双手抱头 快点
Get on your knees,cross them legs, knit them hands, come on.
等等
Ooh, hold on.
你丫要干嘛?
Yo, what the fuck you doing?
你这是闹哪样啊?
What the fuck is wrong with you, man?
把那戒指给我脱了
Hey, give up that ring, man.
快点
Come on.
对了
Yeah.
哈哈 报应
Ha ha ha! Payback.
有种别跑 小兔崽子
That's right. Run, motherfuckers!
操
Shit!
听我准没错
I'm telling you, right there,
这匹马绝对赢
this horse is a winner. Look at it, okay?
你好
How you doing?
等我下
- Hey. - Excuse me.
市长先生
Mr. Mayor.
今天我进城路上看到一辆报废汽车
On my way downtown today I saw an abandoned car.
赶快把它拖走
Tow it right away.
在那儿 市长先生 地址是-
Where is- Mr. Mayor, the location?
妈的 叫交通组
Oh, fucking Christ. Call Transpo!
赶快把该死的拖车开出去
Get the fucking trucks moving!
- 市长先生 - 我接到举报电话
Uh- Mr. Mayor. I got a constituent call.
说她家附近的游乐场有安全隐患
She said the playground near her house was a hazard.
- 废蚀金属 - 我们马上处理
- Rusted metal. - We'll get right on it.
地址 先生 地址是哪儿啊
The location: Sir, I need a location.
市长先生 我明白您的关切 *供水局*
Mr. Mayor, I understand your concern, but you've got to understand,
可我们有9100多个消防龙头啊
we have more than 9,100 hydrants.
其中有一个在漏水
And one of them's leaking.
执法敏感性辅导
Sensitivity counseling,
两周的额外劳动 这点处罚最多了
two week's extra duty, no punishment past that.
他们想大事化小啊
They sliced it into the rough.
Daniels知道背后是Carcetti的意思么?
Does Daniels know the bind this puts his boy Carcetti in?
Wilson交代Rawls Rawls交代Daniels
Well, Wilson briefed Rawls, Rawls briefed Daniels.
Pontius Pilate:古罗马巡官们 比喻将棘手案件转手
Carcetti丢烫山芋呢
It's Carcetti doing Pontius Pilate,
推给Daniels办 不容易出岔子
putting it on Daniels, who was a safe choice
只要官面上过得去
as far as the rank and file goes.
但从长远来看 部长们不会满足于此的
But that won't be enough for the ministers, not by a long shot.
这游戏难不成就我一个人会玩?
Am I the only one that knows how to play this game?
快把那龙头给关了
Let's go, get that hydrant sealed.
三个人 带着手枪
Three of them with shotguns
就在俱乐部门口冲着我来
got me coming outside the club.
这事儿必须血债血偿
I made 'em for bloods.
那油漆摆明了是向我们宣战嘛
The paint's supposed to be some kind of declaration of war.
看来得按照西区的法子
Sounds like we get to stomp some ass.
给他们点颜色瞧瞧
The Western District way.
黄漆算是宣战?
Yellow paint a declaration of war?
真有你的
That's a new one.
我听说三个带种的小混混
So what I heard was that these wild-ass boys-
名字咱不说 有够屌哇
I ain't saying no names- but they past crazy.
明抢了他
They robbed him.
朝他泼了油漆 黄色油漆
They threw paint on his ass- yellow paint.
我可不是吹的
Shit, I ain't lying.
这些我不清楚
Well, I don't know about that,
但你往那箱子上一站也很勇敢嘛
but you showed me something getting on that box like that.
那算啥
That wasn't nothing.
别看轻自己
No, don't sell yourself short.
Duquette老师 Parenti老师 我们都觉得这很有勇气
Ms. Duquette, Mr. Parenti, we all thought it took courage,
尤其是和这样的同学一起
especially considering how y'all do each other.
- 真的? - 嗯
- You think? - Yeah.
你最近在班上进步很大
No, look, you're showing a lot of progress in class.
你也感觉得到吧
I mean, you know that, don't you?
好好做作业 也不再闹事
You know, you're doing the work. You're not acting out.
我看是时间
It's getting to the point where
你回到原来的班上去了
You can go back to regular class, no problem.
- 回普通班? - 嗯
- Back to genpop? - Mm-hmm.
你想我回去吗
You want me to go?
只要你自己愿意啊
Well, if you're ready.
我才不要回去咧
I ain't going back there.
为什么?
Why not?
教的东西无聊死了
Shit they teach there be deadly.
我知道你懂的 Bunny
But I know you know that, Bunny.
好了 好了
All right, all right! All right, all right!
这里那里挤出一点还成
We can squeeze a little money from here and there
但你要的那个数没可能
but nothing on the scale for what you're asking.
也许运作资金里能弄点出来
Maybe free up some operating money
从PAYGO(现收现付)计划里抽一部分
by shifting some of these PAYGO projects
调到财政支出项目
into the capital program.
预算稳定金里也能偷点出来
I can steal a little from the budget stabilization fund,
但是警局这边的缺口
but we still got to absorb 120 grant positions
至少还差12万 还多半是官员加薪
in the police department, mostly officers.
老天 这钱可不敢差
Christ, don't let those go unfunded.
差钱的地方多着呢 学校预算我还没见过
A lot of balls in the air, and I still haven't seen the schools' budget.
税收剩余呢?
What about the revenue surplus?
我说了 这种钱是一次性的
As I said, that's one-time money.
要给警察涨5%薪水 那可是永久性的
If I'm going to give the police a 5% raise, that's forever.
要想让警局去大展拳脚
If I'm going to ask the police department to get up
去冲锋陷阵 必须往里投钱啊
on its hind legs and fight I got to throw some money.
别跟我说这不行那不行 说什么行吧
You're telling me how I can't do it, not how I can.
应急款项倒可以
There's the rainy day fund,
但弄到那个地步真的没必要
but you really shouldn't draw that down.
债券评级署要至少5%的预算储备
The bond rating houses want at least 5% of the budget in reserve.
这不挺紧急的么
Feels like a rainy day to me.
急得要死啊
Cloudy like a motherfucker.
喂 喂 等等
Yo, yo, wait up, yo.
- 想闹哪样啊? - 跟你无关 Mike
- Fuck is up with y'all? - Ain't you, Mike?
我们要和你兄弟谈谈
We wanna have a word with your boy here.
- 又没拦着你 说吧 - 你知道我什么意思
- Ain't nothing stopping you. Talk. - You know what we mean.
你个小婊子给警察打小报告
Yo, the little bitch was talking to the police.
瞎说 我从来没出卖过别人
That's a lie. I ain't been doin' no snitching.
没有你个头
The fuck you ain't.
你看他吓得都快尿裤子了
He look like he about to pee on hisself right now, man.
你该不会跟告密的站一边吧?
You ain't gonna stand by no rat motherfucker, is you?
我不跟告密的站一边
Naw, I ain't standing with no rat.
这东西能保温18小时
These here be them 18-hour junks.
贴上睡了 醒来 还热着呢
Go to bed, wake up, still be hot.
我看你这已经用了三小时了吧
Man, feel this one from three hours ago.
我这不说了嘛 一块钱两包
See what I'm saying? Two for one.
每包两片 买五包我再送您一包
Each pack come with two pads. Buy five, I give you six.
那就来六包吧
Gimmie six then.
五块
Five. Keep toasty.
多谢了您呐 多谢
Obliged, sir, obliged.
往这边 我推这边
Take this side, I'll take this side.
Bubbles百货
Bubbles Depot.
Bubbles百货 应有尽有
Bubbles Depot got what you need.
只管开口 包您不愁
Back on the scene. Come see me.
快看啊 Sherrod!
Oh, looky, looky- hey, Sherrod!
这啥呀
Whoo-ooh. What up?
估摸着是车撞倒的吧
Car must've hit it or some shit.
- 能卖多少? - 铝的?
- How much you think? - Aluminum?
铝算它三四毛一镑
Aluminum about 30-40c a pound.
少说能卖个一百美刀啊乖乖
We've got a Benjamin here easy, baby.
爷俩同心其利断金啊
Teamwork payin' off today, ain't it, baby?
- 嗯 - 你抬重的那头 我再试试
- Yeah. - Go get the heavy side.Let me try it.
让开让开
Get out of the way!
够了啊
That's enough!
快给我滚
Get out of here!
够了 快走
That's enough! Break it up!
Randy 你个贱人
Hey, Randy, you bitch.
别以为我们跟你这告密的算了
We ain't even done with your snitchin' ass.
走吧
Come on, man.
看来书没白念啊
Guess them books are good for something.
快叫护士来
Somebody call the nurse.
他们干吗要揍我?
Yo, why they bank me?
- 我不是告密的 - Randy Randy 没事儿了
- I ain't no snitch. - Randy, Randy, it's okay.
多谢了
Thanks a lot.
卫生局又把George炸鸡店关了?
Health Department shut Chicken George again?
不是 我在这儿避避风头
No, I had to duck in here for cover.
外面满街都是条子
Your boys are off the hook today.
今天在巴尔的摩西区最好别犯傻充愣
Not a good day to be cross-eyed in West Baltimore.
干啥 你们指标未完成还是怎么的?
What, y'all behind on your quotas or some shit?
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
似乎我有个同事昨晚被袭击了
Seems one of my side got jumped last night.
嗯 Walker 我听说了
Yeah, Walker. I heard about that shit.
被泼了油漆
Threw paint on him.
Walker就是个混账
Walker's an asshole.
常在河边走 哪能不湿鞋
Hey, you play in dirt, you get dirty.
7-A-14 收到请回话
7-Adam-14, do you copy?
说吧 KGA
Go ahead, KGA.
北Monroe街19号接报入室抢劫
Report of a burglary 19 North Monroe.
收到
Copy.
下回再聊
We should do this again.
别出去没事找事
Don't go making any furtive moves.
知道
No doubt.
咱连个铅笔尖儿都不敢弄断
Don't break a pencil point.
P老师 我发誓对警察说的都是大家知道的
Mr. P, I swear I only told the police what everybody knows.
这就算告密了吗 Michael?
Does that make me a snitch, Michael?
本来就不该把这事儿对人说
Shouldn't oughta told nobody nothing.
不过告密倒还算不上 你又没把谁弄进去
But that don't make you a snitch, not if you ain't put nobody in.
老天 我就不该让这事发生
Jesus. I should have stopped this.
不是你的错 P先生
It ain't your fault, Mr. P.
这事儿都怪Tiffany
All this come up because of what Tiffany said
在厕所里多嘴
happened in the bathroom.
你到底说什么了Randy? 他们知道点什么?
What did you tell them, Randy? What do they know?
我就告诉他们Lex跟着Fulton去了操场
I just told them about Lex going up to the playground behind Fulton,
然后大家就说他被杀了
and how everybody said he got killed
扔在钉了木板的屋子里
and put in one of them boarded-up houses.
你就说了这些?
That's all you told them?
他们要我说是我亲眼看到的 可...
I mean, they wanted me to say that I was there, but...
我只说了是小Kevin告诉我的
I just told them that Little Kevin told me.
- 小Kevin? - 他也死了
- Little Kevin? - He killed, too.
Marlo捉住了他 大家都这么说
I mean, Marlo got him, too. That's what everybody saying, anyway.
Marlo Stanfield
Marlo Stanfield:
我听说上星期Kevin被关起来了
I heard Kevin got locked up just last week,
现在应该也被封在什么房子里了
now he's supposed to be up in a house somewhere.
他们把他也关了空屋了?
They put him in a vacant, too, huh?
好吧 Randy 眼下要我说听Michael的
Okay, Randy, for now I want to say Michael's right.
要是还有谁找你问话
If anyone tries to talk to you again,
不管谁你一问三不知 记住了?
say nothing to anyone, understand?
这样会好些么?
Will that make it better?
总而言之呢 先生们 上头发话了
So in sum, gentlemen, the gods have spoken.
我们是死是活不再只看数据了
No longer do we live and die by stats.
从今往后 要挑有质量的抓
From this day forward we are about quality arrests-
重罪犯 严重袭击事件
felonies, serious misdemeanors,
像老祖宗们一样老老实实地干活
the back-to-basics police work of our sainted fathers.
说真的 泥塘里开油轮还容易点呢
Still, the truth is it would be easier to turn an oil tanker around in a puddle.
咱们的人就是靠凑数吃饭
Our people were raised on stats.
你要是觉得自己干不了 Eugene
If you can't bend patrol to the mission, Eugene,
我就找别人来干
I'll damn sure find someone who can.
同志们
Gentlemen.
长官
Sir.
根据您提出的议案
Along the line of what you propose,
我想重新建立重案组
I'd like to reconstitute  the Major Crimes Unit,
安插在凶杀组之下
bring it under the umbrella of Homicide.
我猜 你是想大动人事吧
And let me guess, you'd like to shake up the personnel.
适当调整
Where appropriate.
去吧 副总警监
Go for it, Colonel.
怎么了?
What?
够精明啊 在新晋同事面前
Smart move, accepting any ideas
扮好好先生
whatsoever come from the anointed fella.
Daniels呗 下任局长
Daniels. The next commissioner.
在这种才一年多点儿
Any cocksucker that manages to go from
就从警督升到警监的混蛋面前
Iieutenant to full bird in a little more than a year
谁不溜须拍马啊
is getting groomed.
等等 你该不会以为 -
Wait. You didn't for a minute think that-
天哪 Bill 这可是巴尔的摩
Jesus, Bill, it's Baltimore.
我看你不是土生土长的吧?
You ain't one of the natives, are ya?
看到他们往哪儿去了?
You see where they went?
肥仔和竹竿进了个大房间
El gordo and tall man, they go in a big room,
一路
first floor.
门外牌子上写着"New Day Coop"
Sign outside say "New Day Coop."
Coop? 这神马玩意儿?
Coop? What's a coop?
"New Day Coop" 就这么写的
"New Day Coop." That's what it say.
喂 两个O之间是不是有道横线?
Hey, yo, was there like a bar between the two O's?
嗯 没错
Si, exacto.
那是co-op (合作行动)
Yeah, that's co-op.
Joe老大参与合作行动
Prop Joe in a co-op:
Joe和我们打劫过的那人一起进去的
Joe go in with the man we robbed.
记得么 那家伙扑通跪下
Remember, he fell down on his knees,
哭得像个娃娃似的
wept like a little baby.
嗯 胖脸Ricky 还有谁
Yeah, Fat Face Ricky. Anybody else?
差不多八九个我没见过的
Si, como eight or nine others I never see before,
不过看起来都一个样
but all the same to me, you know?
做买卖的
Narcotraficantes.
Joe老大坐不住军中帐了
Prop Joe done sat down to the table.
看看
Oh, do tell.
不想绕圈子了
The worm done came full circle.
Marlo
Marlo.
搞毛?
Que?
要是我想得没错
If that is what I think it is,
这群傻帽看来是准备
our little clutch of chickens might be putting
破釜沉舟了
all their eggs up in one basket.
是好事?
Is good?
好极了 宝贝
Muy bueno, baby.
听我说 要我可不会戴着它到处走
I know one thing- I wouldn't walk around with it on my neck
小心让Walker发现
for Walker to find.
他不会发现的
He ain't gonna find it.
那也不能发疯冒这险
You crazy even taking a chance.
万一他抓住你戴着这个
If he catch you with it,
打断手指算客气的了
he gonna break more than them fingers.
兄弟 你怎么了?
Man, what up with you?
最近你有点...
It's like lately you gone all...
怎么会把面罩给摘了
Iike taking off the mask, yo.
你怎么搞的 万一Walker看到你脸
What up with that? If Walker got a look-
他看不到的
He didn't.
你跟Randy怎么搞的?
Well, what about the thing with you and Randy?
大家都说你为了保护他
Everybody now is sayin' you threw down with him.
把那帮混混打得屁滚尿流
Busted up the boy Dimples, and them.
换你你会袖手旁观?
Yo, you wouldn't have stood tall?
我不是这意思
That's not what I'm saying.
不在于你干什么 在于你怎么干
It's not that you do shit, It's how you do it.
我说...我可不会站一旁
Yo, look, I'm not trying to stand around
让那些白痴觉得老子怕了他们
and let no chump-ass niggers think I'm shook.
妄想
I ain't.
怎样呢
And?
我希望你能加入
And I want you to sign up.
副总警监 此事关系到...
Colonel, there's the matter of-
你担心和某位警督无法相处?
You find yourself incompatibl with a certain lieutenant?
Freamon警官
Detective Freamon,
你将有权随意挑选组员
you have carte blanche in picking your squad.
甚至自行选择上级部门
In fact, you can pick your supervisor for all I care.
他妈的 对我来说
Motherfucker, as far as I'm concerned,
有你就有重案组
you are the Major Crimes Unit.
巴尔的摩的黎明到来了 Lester
It's morning in Baltimore, Lester.
醒来闻闻咖啡香吧
Wake up and smell the coffee.
Carver
Carver.
哟 什么风把你吹来了?
Damn, boy, what brings you back to the plantation?
我相信了你 相信了Daniels 看来我信错人了
I trusted you. Trusted Daniels. My fucking mistake, huh?
等等 出什么事了?
Whoa, hold up. What's wrong?
你们该保护的那个孩子
The kid you were supposed to protect,
居然让他的名字传到街上
you put his name on the street.
今天他当着全校的面被揍了
They were beating him in front of the school today,
被当成告密的暴打
stomping on him for snitching.
- 天 他还好吗 - 都他妈一个鸟样
- Jesus. He all right? - It's always the same.
我早该料到的
I should have fucking seen this coming.
我发誓我什么都不知道
I swear to you, I don't know what happened.
我把这孩子介绍给Bunk Moreland和Herc
I hooked the kid into Bunk Moreland and Herc.
没想到 -
I can't believe-
- 孩子现在在哪儿? - 家里
- where's the kid now? - Home.
等我跟夜班头头说一声
Let me go give this to the night commander.
派个便衣警察去他家
We'll park a plainclothes unit on the house.
你觉得这样有用么
You think that makes it better?
我们会注意保密 在街角看着什么的
We'll be discreet, set up down the block or some shit.
进来吧 我向你保证 我肯定会彻查
Come on inside.I swear to you- I'm gonna find out what happened.
- Ed Bowers - 很高兴见到你
- Ed Bowers. - Pleasure to meet you.
你让我们大跌眼镜啊
You surprised us all.
- 恭喜您 市长先生 - 谢谢
- Congratulations, Mr. Mayor. - Thanks.
这位是贱内Dorothy
- I'd like to introduce you to Dorothy. - ??
这位Ed Nully您认识?
You heard about Ed Nully?
听说过你的作为 好样的 加油
I've heard great things about what you've been doing, so keep it up.
很高兴您能来 市长先生
I'm delighted you made it, Mr. Mayor.
一切为了人民嘛
Well, it's for a good cause, right?
不好意思我要唱红脸了
I am getting the evil eye, however.
得带他多转转
I gotta keep him circulating.
好吧 这边请
Okay. This way.
- 回头见 - 保重
- See you later. - Take care.
华府那帮人现在开始助推本市房地产市场
The Washington crowd is driving the local real estate market now,
如果海滨长廊能延伸至南岸
and if the harbor promenade could extend to the south branch-
- 此事正在研讨中 - 是该研讨
- We're looking at that. - Should be.
从这儿到Hanover街是寸土寸金啊
Everything from here to Hanover Street is money.
市长先生 平时打不打牌啊?
Mr. Mayor, play a little poker?
我手气不好
I'm not very lucky.
手气是会变的嘛
Luck can change.
市长先生 介绍您认识下Ray Chandler
Mr. Mayor, I'd like you to meet Ray Chandler.
很高兴认识您
Pleasure to meet you.
你再不剪 我动手了
Boy, either you gonna do it, or I'm gonna.
就你这样 也难怪条子总找你茬
There's a reason the police keep jumping out on you, Na'.
这是Bunk的古龙水味儿么
So, was it the Bunk's cologne, huh?
是女人的
Oh... pussy.
我也会想你的 杂种
I'm gonna miss you, too, bitch.
Lester不就喜欢听别人的电话么
Lester do love listening to other  people's phone calls, don't you?
小心变成变态哟
A bit of a pervert that way.
你就不会偶尔用监听破几个案子么
You could use a wiretap case or two-
就当开开眼界
broaden your horizons.
不不
Oh, no no.
咱Bunk可是西装革履地干活
The Bunk is strictly a suit-and-tie motherfucker.
世道再混乱 也要一表人才地出去
At all hazards, a man must keep up appearances.
尊严 尊严至上 大人
Dignity, I say. Dignity above al  Governor. Hear, hear!
Bunk 有时间么
Bunk, you got a minute?
- 怎么了? - 我送过来的那个姓Wagstaff的小子
- What's up? - The Wagstaff kid I sent your way.
Wagstaff? 你给送我这儿了?
Wagstaff? He one of mine?
是啊 你不是在找Lex么
Yeah, you were looking for the boy Lex,
几个月前在夜总会门口开枪打了别人的
shot someone outside a nightclub a couple of three months back.
这孩子知道Lex被杀了
This kid knew about Lex getting killed.
Herc带他来见你的
Herc brought him to you.
Herc
Herc:
这孩子是目击证人  Herc本该要带来见我的
This kid is a witness, and Herc was supposed to bring him to me?
按理说是啊
That was the plan.
看我不把这小子活剥了
I'm gonna skin that motherfucker.
天 Herc 你他妈干了什么?
Jesus, Herc. The fuck did you do?
那孩子出事儿了?
Something happen to that boy?
年轻人 你们的愿望成真了
Well, young man, your wish has come true.
我总算能出去了?
So this mean I can finally get out of here?
对 Monnel 文件还要慢慢从北街传过来
Yes, Monnel, paperwork was slow coming in from North Avenue,
但以你们的年龄 我们觉得是时候
but you five are at the age where we feel it's to your advantage
加入同学们 回到九年级了
to join your peers in the ninth grade.
我们要进高中了!
Yo, we in high school!
- 什么时候去 - 本轮评估结束
- When we bump? - The end of this marking period.
恭喜你们
Congratulations.
好了 解散吧
You're excused.
Johnson先生 前台有人找
Mr. Johnson, you have a visitor in the front office.
Johnson先生 请速至前台
Mr. Johnson, please come down to the front office.
坏消息
Bad news:
会有更多的人来视察
Plenty more to go around.
他们要撤掉你的项目
They pulled the pin on your program.
正如我过去一周以来在各区大会上所说
As I've been saying this week at every roll call in every damn district,
能搜刮出来的 我都拿出来了
if I could scrape together any more, I would.
作为开始 每年一视同仁 加薪5%
But for starters, it's a 5% salary year, and that's a given.
虽然和大家的努力比起来微不足道
I know it's not half what you deserve,
但今后财政收入稳定的话 我保证将会继续加薪
but if the revenue estimates stay good, I promise you'll be seeing more.
市长先生
Mr. Mayor,
我老婆谢谢您 我孩子谢谢您
my wife thanks you, my children thank you,
我的狗也谢谢您
my dog thanks you.
Santy 你怎么分得出你老婆和你的狗啊
Hey, Santy, how you able to tell your wife from your mutt?
长虱子的那个准是他老婆
His wife, she's the one that's got the fleas.
放屁Bobby 你老婆身上长的
Shit, Bobby, with your old lady,
比虱子还不如呢
fleas would be an improvement.
好了 市长在这儿呢
At ease. We got the mayor here, gentlemen.
他们在一个地方坐久了皮痒
When they sit in one place too long they get a little feisty.
我不会站在这里假装对你们的工作了如指掌
I'm not going to stand here and pretend I know how to do your job.
不会 但在过去几个星期里
I don't. But what I can tell you is that during the past few weeks
我和许多你们的同事聊过
I have spoken with many of your peers,
和工会代表聊过 和FOP代表聊过
with your union reps, with the representatives of the FOP,
我听到的最大不满
and the biggest single complaint I'm hearing
就是警局内部只重指标的风气
concerns the department's obsession with stats.
都他妈是数字游戏
The fucking numbers game.
在我眼皮底下数字游戏将不复存在
Well, under my watch the numbers game is over.
大家不用被枪指着完成每月任务
You will no longer be under the gun to meet monthly quotas
靠抓些无关痛痒的人来滥竽充数
of ineffective, meaningless arrests and citations.
抱歉 领导 但你不是第一个站上讲台
Excuse me, Your Worship. You're not the first person
拍胸脯保证的人
who stood at the podium making promises.
Jimmy 市长肯定还有其他要事
Jimmy, I'm sure the mayor has some pressing business.
我只是说 要是什么热心群众打电话
No, I'm just saying, the first community activist
说她家小区有人违法犯事儿啥的
who pitches a bitch about the corner activity in her neighborhood,
难道我们就干坐着不去抓人?
aren't we gonna go right back to rounding up bodies?
我们必须教育市民适应新的执法程序
Yeah, well, we need to educate our citizens to the new approach.
要教育的不只是市民
Well, they're not the only ones who need educating.
有好些对警务工作屁事儿不懂的头头
We got bosses that wouldn't know police work if it bit 'em in the ass.
这么多年只知道抓指标 你指望他们怎么改
They been juking stats for years, and they'll do it again
一旦有人投诉 他们肯定怪咱
once the neighborhoods complain. It's all they know.
要是老家伙们办事不力
Well, if the old dogs can't get the job done,
我就找能干的来干
I'll find new ones who can.
我在市政厅坐了那么多年冷板凳
Look, for years I sat on the back bench of the council
看着我们城市日渐堕落
and watched our city deteriorate.
老观念不改改
It was business as usual with the same old ideas
怎么可能有新的结果
producing the same old results.
今天我和大家共处一室 我只想说
Well, I'm here now, as you are, and I'm asking you
请大家抛开成见 放手一搏
to put aside your reservations and give it a go.
完毕
All told.
干得不错
You did good.
很会鼓舞士气啊 他们爱戴你
You got 'em pumped. They love you.
虽然Hauk警官那步棋走得不妙
Of course, the wrong decision on Sergeant Hauk,
不过谁知道呢?
and who knows?
Carv说这孩子有情报 我就跟他聊了聊
Carv said the kid had something on it. I talked to him.
结果没什么 一堆废话
He had nothing, just a bunch of hearsay
说了什么僵尸什么的
and some shit about zombies.
这孩子本该送我这儿来
The boy was to come to me.
你知道规矩的 凶杀组说了算
You know the goddamn GO- it's Homicide's call.
你上我的案子里趟什么浑水 你个混账
You don't go putting your paws in my murder, you simple fuck.
你可是在对警长说话
Hey! You're talking to a sergeant.
- 有杠杠了不起啊! - 喂喂 别激动 Bunk
- Oh, fuck your fucking stripes! - Whoa whoa, take it easy, Bunk.
Herc也是在帮我们
Now Herc is trying to help us here.
他插手我的谋杀案 他负责
Man, he messed in my murder, he pays.
给他个机会嘛 咱一起想办法
Give him a chance. We can work something out.
你说得倒轻巧 又不是你负责
That's easy for you to say. You ain't the primary on this.
狗娘养的...
Motherfucker...
他怎么搞的
What got into him?
火气大
He's emotional.
为这案子忙活太久了
He's been working this case for a long time.
现在你要做的就是回忆
So the thing right now is for you to remember
参与这案子的每个细节...
everything you did on this case...
从头说起
from the beginning.
他站在外面捏着帽子 真的
He's out there, hat in hand, literally.
让他等到天荒地老好了
Well, he can wait till hell freezes over.
聪明人懂得要想拆桥
A wise man does not burn his bridges
得先知道怎么过河才行
until he first knows he can part the waters.
古Ashanti人的谚语
Old Ashanti saying.
Norman 你可是Catonsville本地人
Norman, you grew up in Catonsville.
让那混蛋进来吧
Show the motherfucker in.
市长先生
Mr. Mayor,
我无意打扰您的繁忙日程
I don't want to take time out of your busy schedule.
如果你来是为了我反驳你多抓指标的命令...
Look, if this is about me countermanding your orders for more arrests-
不 这事儿您根据情况办就是了
No, sir. You should proceed as you feel the situation warrants.
怎么说 警务政策也不是我的强项
Overall, policing strategies may not be my strongest suit.
我来是为了干我的本职工作
I'm here about what I do know.
明天Hauk警长的指挥官
A recommendation from Sergeant Hauk's commander
会把推荐信送到您桌上
will cross your desk tomorrow.
Daniels副总警监 Rawls也同意了
Colonel Daniels, with Rawls concurring,
建议执法敏感性训练
recommends sensitivity training.
应该是公平的决策
It may be a fair decision,
甚至可以说是正确的决策
it may even be the right decision.
但我们都知道部长们是不会善罢甘休的
But we both know it won't fly with the ministers,
就算Daniels主事也没用
not even with Daniels behind it.
哼
Hmm.
600页的法律法规
600 pages of rules,
指导原则
regulations, directives, orders.
你要是因为一白人警察错拦黑人部长车
You fire a white police for a bad car stop
而炒了他 员佐级别不会乐意的
on a black minister, you'll lose the rank and file.
这原因不够 但有了这玩意儿
It's not cause enough. But if a commander can't find
连圣人都不愁炒不掉
grounds for firing a saint in here...
这人在缉毒部门干了六年了
The man has worked Narcotics for six years,
干缉毒的 没一个干净的
and in Narcotics there are no virgins.
这就是你所谓的专长了?
And herein lies your expertise?
制定战略什么的我一向愿意放手
I've always been comfortable delegating strategic elements.
不然要副局长们干嘛
It's what the Deputy Ops is for.
我嘛 我清楚市长的需要
Me, I know what a mayor needs.
- 是辆雪弗兰太浩 - 嗯
- It was a Chevy Tahoe. - Mm-hmm.
车牌 M-460-654
License Mike-460-654.
我仔细搜了 指望着能找到武器 可...
And I searched it good, figuring I'd find some iron, but-
他们什么反应?
How'd they react?
Chris and Snoop? 他们动都没动
Chris and Snoop? They didn't do shit.
车里有什么?
Was there anything in the car?
驾照和垃圾在储物箱里
Registration and crap in the glove box,
空的炸鸡盒子 垃圾
empty chicken boxes, trash.
他们有个那种塑料牛奶箱
They had one of those plastic milk crates-
- 嗯 - 后备箱有些工具
- Mm-hmm. - in the back with some tools in it.
什么样的工具?
What kind of tools?
不知道 木工的吧
I don't know, carpenter tools.
你搜了牛奶箱没有?
Did you check the crate for weapons?
- 汽钉枪 - 汽钉枪?
- Nail gun. - Nail gun?
就是那种钉钉子用的
Yeah, one of them bitches that shoots nails.
他们改装过了用来射击?
They rig it to shoot rounds maybe?
不 我试过了 就蹦出一钉子
Naw, I shot it. A nail came out.
Lester 真的 说这些有用吗?
Look, Lester, seriously, is any of this helping?
你做得很好
Naw, you're doing good.
跟我说说在火车站逮捕Marlo的事儿
Tell me about jacking Marlo at the train station.
说我差四块?
I'm short four, right?
我记得你这货
Yeah, I remember your ass.
给你四下尝尝 喜欢不?
Here's my four. You like that?
- 好了! - 看我不揍死你
- Okay! - I'm gonna beat your ass.
够了 别打了 住手住手
Okay, no more! Stop stop stop stop.
钱拿去 给你钱还不行么
Take the money, take the money, all right?
再惹毛老子 看我不剥了你们的皮!
Make me work this hard again, I'm gonna skin one of y'all!
好了 你走吧
Okay. Just go, man.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, man.
你知道什么人臀翘逼紧么?
You know who got the fattest asses and the best pussy?
- 谁哇? - 侏儒呗 黑鬼
- Who that? - Midgets, nigger.
- 都那样的 懂我什么意思吧? - 扯吧
They're all that, you know what I'm saying?
门外的兄弟怎么了?
The fuck happened to our boy on the door?
午睡呢 老爹
Siesta, Papa.
把这修好吧 Joe?
You fix this, Joe?
出什么事儿了?
What's the problem?
没时间了
Ran out of time.
Joe 你倒是挺会打马虎眼
Now, Joe, you've been so busy being devious,
到处瞎转悠闯到盘丝洞里去了
you done messed around and got yourself caught up in a web.
Omar 我不知道你听说了些什么
Omar, I don't know what you been hearing, now-
Joe 没时间扯谎了
Joe, ain't no time for no lies now.
你给我老老实实地
Now see, I need you to be straight,
就像你参加New Day合作行动那样坐好了
just like you did on that New Day Co-op sit down.
没错 我知道了
Oh, yeah, I know about that.
我还知道是你把Marlo扯进这趟浑水
I know you the one got Marlo up in this mess too.
喂 Omar 深吸一口气
Hey, Omar, take a deep breath.
让我给你提个好心的建议
A proposition might fall kindly on your ear.
想拍马屁了 肥猪
Well, tickle my fancy, fat man.
要钱要药随您便
Money, drugs- your call.
喂 Joe 别拿这些来糊弄我
Come on, now, Joe, you can do better than that.
这样子不对啊
Hey, we- we coming at this all wrong.
你是拿着枪的那个
See, you the one with the high card.
要什么应该你说嘛
You should speak your mind.
你要好好伺候下Marlo
You going to serve up Marlo.
你想把Marlo Stanfield端了?
You gonna take out Marlo Stanfield?
不不 但我有种强烈的欲望 要把他所有的一切占为己有
No no, but I got a real powerful urge to take everything he owns,
我相信你是办成此事的最佳人选
and I'm quite confident you the man can make that happen.
这事儿得费些周折
That might take some doing.
不不 怎么简单怎么来
Naw naw, see, we got to have it simple.
看到吧 Omar喜欢简单的
See, Omar like it simple.
那么我们怎么办呢?
So how we gonna do this, yo?
啊
Huh:
我姐姐的儿子
My sister's boy.
他负责送货
He do the drop.
我打电话给你 告诉你地点
We call you and give up the spot.
- 够简单了吧 - 就这么办
- That simple enough? - That's what it is.
听好了 Joe 我要你好好管着自己
See now, Joe, I need you to resist your natural inclination
别妄想暗中搞什么破坏 明白了?
to do anything twisted up in this here play. You feel me?
要是让老子闻到一点不对头 Joe
I even catch a whiff of you doing something foul, Joe,
可别怪我告诉Marlo
I mean, I might got to go tell Marlo you the one
是你把我推上牌局的
put me up on that card game.
听懂了?
We understood?
快给我写张收据我要走了
Now go ahead and write my ticket so I can tip on out.
快啊
Come on now.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我去看看Tremaine
I'll see to Tremaine.
- 你开玩笑呢吧 - 你没听见吗
- You can't be serious. - Was you listening?
Omar站在一边拿着个铁锹
Omar to one side holding a spade,
不然就是Marlo站在另一边拿着铲子
and maybe Marlo to the other with a shovel.
眼下这当口
And just at this moment,
老子好不容易从自己的坟墓里爬出来
I managed to crawl out my own damn grave.
我可不准备再爬回去
No way do I crawl back in.
你他娘的在这儿干啥呢?
What the fuck was you doing out here, man?
你相信他?
You trust him?
- 我相信他怕了 - 我们能走了吧?
- I trust his fear. - Now we go, si?
先得教会Prop Joe什么叫姜还是老的辣
Not till I teach Prop Joe a thing or two about devious.
现在盯他
We on him now.
对不起我无话可说 你们跟孩子妈说去
Sorry, guys, that's all I got to say. Talk to the mom.
我知道了 但我们刚从他养母那儿过来
I hear you, but we just came from his foster mother's house,
她说是你让她不要开口的
and she said it was you that told him not to talk.
她说你还让她找律师去
She said you told her to get a lawyer.
没错
That's right.
好吧 我知道出了点岔子
All right, look, something got messed up.
我们知道 但是不管怎样
We know that, but whatever else happened,
- 这总是起谋杀案 - 就算不作为正式记录
- we got a murder here. - Even if it's off the record,
能和这孩子谈谈总也有好处的
it would help us just to talk to the boy.
如果你们知道发生了什么
If you understand what happened here,
就理解为什么我不会同意了
you know I'm not gonna do that.
如果你坚持这种态度 那最后其实是站在
If you go at it like that, then you end up
那帮杀人越货的混蛋一边
siding with the motherfuckers doing the dirt.
不 我当然是站在孩子们这边
No, I'm siding with my kids.
你说得对 你说得对
You're right. You're right.
对你 孩子们是第一位的
For you, the kids come first.
我们另想法子
We'll find another road.
你在这里干得高兴就好
Well, glad this is working out for you.
你们俩...
Oh, man, you two...
我快潸然泪下了都
makin' me all weepy and shit.
- 保重 - 好
- Be safe, guys. - All right.
喂 Roland
Hey, Roland, man,
你看我大老远跑来
you know, I hate coming all this way
一点消息都得不到也太...
and not getting a little something...
看在咱俩交情份上吧?
you know, for old times' sake?
Fulton和Monroe街后的操场
The playground behind Fulton and Monroe,
小平房
unit block.
他给兄弟Lex传话说有个姑娘要见他
He told this fella Lex to meet a girl there.
仅此而已
That's all he did.
小个子? 给我拿三包?
What's up, Shorty? Can you give me three?
贱人 给我滚街对面去
Bitch, get the fuck across the street
老实点坐墩子上
and plant your ass on a stoop.
Kenard!
你觉得我把辫子剪了怎么样?
Yo, how do you think I look with no tail on my head?
你当我基佬啊?
Do I look like a faggy?
喂 Na
Yo, Na'.
Lee太太 你找Michael?
Yo, Mrs. Lee, you looking for Michael?
不 Namond 我也不想麻烦你
Um, Namond, I don't want to be no trouble to you,
但我有个朋友她瘾儿上来了
but I got this friend who been ailing,
给了我6美元
you know, and she gave me $6.
我想着你能不能...
So I was hoping you could, you know...
行吧 算我们的 去找我弟兄吧
Yeah, we cover her. Go see my man.
你这算怎么回事儿?
The fuck you do that for?
这是Michael的妈啊
It's Michael's moms, yo.
- 呸 什么大烟鬼朋友 - Namond说行的
- Shit, she a fucking dope fiend. - Namond said I could.
- Na' - 嗯 给她吧
- Na' - Naw, it's cool.
给我黄的
Gimme Yellow Bird.
知道了 知道我晚了
I know, I know! I'm late, you know?
有时候做老大实在是太好玩了
Sometimes it's just too much damn fun being in charge.
你去哪儿了 老板?
Where you been, boss?
向权威机构述职
Announcing my presence with authority.
抱歉我迟到了 大家请坐
Sorry I'm late. Please sit down. Sit.
先生 我们拖走了52辆废车
Sir, we scarfed up 52 vehicles.
好 偏偏漏了我的车
Good. But you missed my car.
我们给45校区 52校区和58校区
We have new equipment at school 45,
装了新活动设施
school 52, and school 58 installed.
我接到的电话不是那儿的  不过加油干 总会办到的 我保证
Well, I got no calls on those, but keep at it. You'll get there, I'm sure.
市长先生 截止今天所有消防龙头全部加盖
Mr. Mayor, all hydrants are fully capped as of today,
清道部门从街头巷尾扫出了32吨垃圾
and solid waste has pulled 32 tons of trash
这还是今天一天的记录
from the alleys, and, sir, that's a single-day record.
这才是我想听到的
That's what I want to hear.
谢谢各位 请务必再接再励
Thank you, gentlemen, and keep up the good work.
财政嘛 要是十指不沾灰
Finance, of course, doesn't deal with
是搞不上去的
the dirt-under- the-nails tangibles,
除非沾的钱就是脏的
unless you consider the money itself to be dirty.
- 你今天干了些什么? - 学校审计
- So what's in your agenda today? - The school audit.
有多糟糕?
Well, how bad could that be?
整个教育系统存在五千四百万美元赤字
The system is running a $54 million deficit.
五千四百万?
54 million?
是的 市长先生
Yes, Mr. Mayor.
老天啊 Royce知道吗?
Jesus Christ. Did Royce know this?
这烂摊子该怎么收拾啊?
How the fuck do we deal with that?
老实说我也不知道该怎么办
Frankly, I'm not sure just yet.
我们的出勤率非常好
Our attendance is excellent,
没有任何被停学的
and as to suspensions, we don't have any.
有问题立即处理
We intervene immediately,
在稳定行为方面也有很大成功
and we show success in stabilizing behavior.
更别提对孩子们本身的种种好处了
Not to mention the world of good we're doing for the classes
我们开课前这些孩子都快废了
these kids were wrecking before the program.
到一月份我们可以扩展至四个班
In January we could expand to four classes,
涵盖整个八年级
cover the whole eighth grade.
有什么关于跟踪调查的投诉吗
Any complaints about the tracking,
- 家长方面的 - 一起都没有
- anything from the parents? - Not a one.
这不是那种家长踊跃参与的项目
This isn't a group where we see a lot of parental intervention.
考试成绩呢?
What about test scores?
参加项目的学生我不敢说
I can't speak to the program itself,
但八年级其他班平均分肯定是上去了
but it has to help the rest of the eighth grade.
下星期就见分晓
Next week will tell.
目前教育系统正在接受种种考察
Right now the system  is under a lot of scrutiny.
我们面临大量牵涉到办学的财政问题
We have certain fiscal issues that are of great concern to the new administrration,
而你们提出的这些个项目 是对教育体制的重大改革
and what you're proposing here is a radical shift in curricula.
- 怎讲? - 如果市政厅要求这么干
- Meaning? - If City Hall were to sign off on this,
我们肯定放行
we could go forward,
但现在最好不要出这个风头
but now is not the tim to rock any boats.
听见没? 这才是哥的路子
Hear that? That's my joint right there.
你的活都干完了?
So you all got your work up to date, right?
是啊 是啊 是啊
Yeah yeah yeah.
听说你帮手下小弟解决了问题
I heard you took care of your puppy's problems.
这问题可是一江春水向东流了
Oh, he most definitely made that go away, you hear me?
那就好
It's all good.
街上有些小兄弟们在说
You know, some of the young'uns been saying
你兄弟为个告密的挺身而出
your pup stood tall with a snitchin' boy.
Michael
Michael:
他们是这么说的
Yeah, that's what they saying.
- 哦? - 嗯
- Huh. - Yeah.
Lester 你吓到我了 兄弟
Lester, you really starting to scare me, man.
- 我要根撬棒 - 干嘛
- Need a crowbar. - For what:
这是个坟墓
This is a tomb.
Lex就在这里面
Lex is in there.
哦...
Oh...
我操
fuck me.